Joaquin Armando Camara Rivera

Go Engineer

I am a software engineer who has been working with a variety of applications. Specialized in Golang, JavaScript and some front-end frameworks and libraries such as React.js, Redux.js, Meteor.js, Node.js, express.js, media-soup, React-Native and other technologies like CSS, HTML and HTTPS. I truly believe that anyone can be a good mentor regardless of their age or knowledge.

| EDUCATION

Universidad modelo Mexico (2009 - 2013)

Business management

Unadm Mexico (2014 - 2018)

Software development engineering

| WORKING EXPERIENCES

Encora (2021 - Present)

Go developer and senior Front-end Developer

Creating CMS for client Qmerit. Qmerit is a platform dedicated to connect certificated electricians to give electrical car's chargers installations.

Technologies: Go, HTML5, React, Javascript, CSS3, Flexbox, Webpack,, NodeJS, Express, Sass, Python and Redux.

KSquare Group(2018 - 2020)

Mid Javascript Developer

GES Mobile App:

- Worked on the front-end of the app with react native for android and iOS.

Responsibilities:

- Create a prototype in React-Native implementing the design delivered by the design team.
- Technologies: React-Native, JSX, JavaScript.

Javascript with NodeSchool technology:

- Designing the Javascript trainee program with node school technology.

Responsibilities:

- Select the topics for the different stages of the Javascript training process.
- Technologies: Node.js and JavaScript.

JavaScript Talks:

- Leading an internal project of talks with topics about Javascript and related technologies in english for the Javascript team can practice their technical english.

 JavaScript Interviewer:
- interviewer for aspiring juniors javascript developers.

Zanma LSM:

- Worked with the front-end team in the design implementation, the implementation of SCORM and AICC courses and giving support to the others teams of the project with opinions and advices.

Responsibilities:

- Perform the taking of requirements with the client.
- Design the architecture of the application.
- Design the calendar of activities for the front-end programming team.
- Design the structure of the Store to implement Redux.
- Design, together with the backend team, the structure of the base database.
- Integrate the APIs generated by the Back-end team.
- Apply the design and logic of operation in the front-end.
- Direct the meetings with the client for the demonstration of modules and advances.
- Integrate SCORM courses with the LMS system.

Technologies: React.js, TypeScript, JSX, Redux, CSS, SCORM, AICC.

Boy Scouts of America mobile app:

- Worked on the front-end of the app with react native for android and iOS.

Responsibilities:

- Integrate the APIs generated by the Back-end team.
- Perform the front end equipment code reviews.
- Apply the design and logic of operation in the front-end.

MiConcierge (JUN - OCT 2018)

Web Developer

Description:

Mobile app for the tourism industry where independent promoters earn money for recommending and selling tourism products.

Worked at:

- MiConcierge restaurants admin website.
- MiConcierge sellers admin website.

Responsibilities:

- Perform the taking of requirements with the client.
- Design the architecture of the application.
- Design the calendar of activities for the front-end programming team.
- Design the structure of the Store to implement Redux.
- Design, together with the backend team, the structure of the base database.
- Integrate the APIs generated by the Back-end team.
- Apply the design and logic of operation in the front-end.
- Direct the meetings with the client for the demonstration of modules and advances.
- Create and configure the base project with React-Native, Apollo-Graph-QL, Redux, push notifications and Fire Base.
- Link: https://www.miconcierge.mx/

Ativarsoft (2017 - 2018)

I Frontend Developer

Buxx mobile app

Description: Buxx is a mobile application, in which businesses such as restaurants, bars,

veterinarians, etc. promote their services, events, promotions and information, in the same way so

that customers can exchange coupons with businesses in Mérida Yucatán.

Responsibilities:

- Perform the taking of requirements with the client.

- Design the architecture of the application.

- Design the calendar of activities for the front-end programming team.

- Design the structure of the Store to implement Redux.

- Design, together with the backend team, the structure of the base database.

- Integrate the APIs generated by the Back-end team.

- Apply the design and logic of operation in the front-end.

- Direct the meetings with the client for the demonstration of modules and advances.

- Create and configure the base project with React-Native, Apollo-Graph-QL, Redux, push

notifications and Fire Base.

Link: https://www.buxx.mx/

Technologies: React-Native, JSX, Fire base, GraphQL, react-apollo, Redux.

Fhamy website:

Description: Fhamy is a platform similar to amazon so that artisans can sell their products in

different markets.

Responsibilities:

- Perform the taking of requirements with the client.

- Design the architecture of the application.

- Design the calendar of activities for the front-end programming team.

- Design the calendar of activities for the back-end programming team.

- Design, together with the backend team, the structure of the base database.

- Integrate the APIs generated by the Back-end team.

- Perform the front end equipment code reviews.

- Apply the design and logic of operation in the front-end.

Link: https://www.fhamy.mx/

Technologies: React.js, Meteor.js, MongoDB, Heroku, HTML, CSS3, Bootstrap and Redux.

| Personal projects:

Alchemist:

Alchemist.go it's a command cli powered by Go, it's commands allow you to transmute projects with React.js for the client app and Go for the backend api.

URL: https://github.com/joaquincamara/alchemist

Pixel-desk-os:

It's just a little OS powered by Javascript and React.js

URL: https://joaquincamara.github.io/pixel-desk-os/#/home

SKILLS

- HTML5/CSS/JavaScript
- SASS
- TypeScript
- React
- Redux
- NodeJS
- npm
- Flexbox
- Golang
- Git

I LANGUAGES

English (Professional Proficiency) Spanish (Native)